PG 740, Frank A. Lajoie and Gary J. Horton World War I Poster Collection
Connecticut State Library
Frank A. Lajoie and Gary J. Horton World War I Poster collection
circa 1917-1918
Connecticut State Library
Lajoie, Francis A.
Horton, Gary J.
.25 cubic feet (29 posters)
Frank A. Lajoie was business manager of the business office for the Meriden Record Co. in Meriden where he collected the 29 World War I posters found in this collection.
PG740
2014-005
Biographical Note
Francis (Frank) A. Lajoie was born on November 3, 1880 to David and Salina Codette Lajoie in Meriden, Connecticut. Francis married Alma Munn on June 15, 1910, at St. Laurent's Church in Meriden. He was business manager of the business office for the Meriden Record Co. in Meriden where he collected the World War I posters found in this collection. He then went on to work for the Aetna Life Insurance Company in Hartford for 40 years retiring in 1958. Francis A. Lajoie died in Willimantic, Windham County, Connecticut on July 12, 1979.
Genealogy
Francis (Frank) A. and Alma Munn Lajoie were married in 1910. In 1921, they had a daughter Vivian Shirley Lajoie. Vivian and John Edmund Horton were married on September 8, 1945. Vivian and John Horton had four children: Gregory, Gail, Gary, and James. Gary J. Horton is the grandson of Francis A. Lajoie.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of 29 World War I posters.
Index Terms
Subjects:
World War, 1914-1918 -- Posters; War posters -- United States; World War, 1914-1918 -- United States; Connecticut State Council of Defense
Persons:
Horton, Gary J.; Lajoie, Francis A.
Document Types:
Posters
Restrictions on Access
See the policy.
Provenance
The Frank A. Lajoie and Gary J. Horton World War I Poster collection was donated by Gary J. Horton to the Connecticut State Library on May 30, 2013.
List of Posters
- Posters, circa 1917-1918
  - "Federal Warning Against Non-Essential New Enterprises…Resolution Passed by War Industries Board…The Connecticut State Council of Defense Calls the Attention of the People of This State to the Following:-...", circa 1917-1918 (Box 1)
  - "Fighting in France for Freedom!-Are YOU Helping at Home?", News Photo Poster No. 8 issued for Connecticut State Council of Defense, circa 1917-1918 (Box 1)
  - "Fighting in France for Freedom!-Are YOU Helping at Home?", News Photo Poster No. 9 issued for Connecticut State Council of Defense, circa 1917-1918 (Box 1)
  - "Fighting in France for Freedom!-Are YOU Helping at Home?", News Photo Poster No. 10 issued for Connecticut State Council of Defense, circa 1917-1918 (Box 1)
  - "Fighting in France for Freedom!-Are YOU Helping at Home?", News Photo Poster No. 12 issued for Connecticut State Council of Defense, circa 1917-1918 (Box 1)
  - "Fighting in France for Freedom!-Are YOU Helping at Home?", News Photo Poster No. 13 issued for Connecticut State Council of Defense, circa 1917-1918 (Box 1)
  - "Fighting in France for Freedom!-Are YOU Helping at Home?", News Photo Poster No. 14 issued for Connecticut State Council of Defense, circa 1917-1918 (Box 1)
  - "Fighting in France for Freedom!-Are YOU Helping at Home?", News Photo Poster No. 15 issued for Connecticut State Council of Defense, circa 1917-1918 (Box 1)
  - "Fighting in France for Freedom!-Are YOU Helping at Home?", News Photo Poster No. 16 issued for Connecticut State Council of Defense, circa 1917-1918 (Box 1)
  - "Fighting in France for Freedom!-Are YOU Helping at Home?", News Photo Poster No. 17 issued for Connecticut State Council of Defense, circa 1917-1918 (Box 1)
  - "Fighting in France for Freedom!-Are YOU Helping at Home?", News Photo Poster No. 18 issued for Connecticut State Council of Defense, circa 1917-1918 (Box 1)
  - "Fighting in France for Freedom!-Are YOU Helping at Home?", News Photo Poster No. 19 issued for Connecticut State Council of Defense, circa 1917-1918 (Box 1)
  - "Fighting in France for Freedom!-Are YOU Helping at Home?", News Photo Poster No. 20 issued for Connecticut State Council of Defense, circa 1917-1918 (Box 1)
  - "Fighting in France for Freedom!-Are YOU Helping at Home?", News Photo Poster No. 21 issued for Connecticut State Council of Defense, circa 1917-1918 (Box 1)
  - "Fighting in France for Freedom!-Are YOU Helping at Home?", News Photo Poster No. 22 issued for Connecticut State Council of Defense, circa 1917-1918 (Box 1)
  - "Fighting in France for Freedom!-Are YOU Helping at Home?", News Photo Poster No. 23 issued for Connecticut State Council of Defense, circa 1917-1918 (Box 1)
  - "Fighting in France for Freedom!-Are YOU Helping at Home?", News Photo Poster No. 25 issued for Connecticut State Council of Defense, circa 1917-1918 (Box 1)
  - "Fighting in France for Freedom!-Are YOU Helping at Home?", News Photo Poster No. 26 issued for Connecticut State Council of Defense, circa 1917-1918 (Box 1)
  - "Fighting in France for Freedom!-Are YOU Helping at Home?", News Photo Poster No. 27 issued for Connecticut State Council of Defense, circa 1917-1918 (Box 1)
  - "Fighting in France for Freedom!-Are YOU Helping at Home?", News Photo Poster No. 29 issued for Connecticut State Council of Defense, circa 1917-1918 (Box 1)
  - "Fighting in France for Freedom!-Are YOU Helping at Home?", News Photo Poster No. 30 issued for Connecticut State Council of Defense, circa 1917-1918 (Box 1)
  - "Fighting in France for Freedom!-Are YOU Helping at Home?", News Photo Poster No. 31 issued for Connecticut State Council of Defense, circa 1917-1918 (Box 1)
  - "My Soldier...How Can You Help? WSS Save WSS Buy War Stamps - Keep on Buying", circa 1917-1918 (Box 1)
  - "Remember the Boys in France!-Write Them Often", News Photo Poster No. 32 issued for Connecticut State Council of Defense, circa 1917-1918 (Box 1)
  - "Remember the Boys in France!-Write Them Often", News Photo Poster No. 33 issued for Connecticut State Council of Defense, circa 1917-1918 (Box 1)
  - "Remember the Boys in France!-Write Them Often", News Photo Poster No. 34 issued for Connecticut State Council of Defense, circa 1917-1918 (Box 1)
  - "State of Connecticut, Executive Chambers, Hartford...To the Citizens of Connecticut…In the nation-wide movement to collect $100,000,000 for the Second War Fund of the American Red Cross...", circa 1917-1918 (Box 1)
  - United States Fuel Administration, State Capitol, Hartford, Conn., "Regulations Established by the Fuel Administration", circa 1917-1918 (Box 1)
  - "Your President and Your Governor Endorse the Children's Year...What will YOU do to HELP SAVE 1056 BABIES In Connecticut in 1918? Woman's Committee, Connecticut State Council of Defense, Room 66, State Capitol, Hartford, Connecticut", circa 1917-1918 (Box 1)